int currentQuestionIndex = 0;

//Screen own
List<Map<String, dynamic>> questions = [
  {
    'question': 'What is Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A mobile app development framework',
      'A social media platform',
      'A new programming language',
      'A video game'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A mobile app development framework',
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the name of the Flutter widget used for building responsive layouts?',
    'answers': ['GridView', 'ListView', 'Wrap', 'Row'],
    'correctAnswer': 'Wrap'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the name of the package used for building responsive layouts in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'responsive_layout',
      'flutter_responsive',
      'flutter_layout',
      'flutter_screenutil'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'flutter_screenutil'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which widget can be used to specify a percentage-based width in Flutter?',
    'answers': ['Expanded', 'Flexible', 'SizedBox', 'AspectRatio'],
    'correctAnswer': 'Expanded'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the name of the Flutter widget used for building responsive dialogs?',
    'answers': [
      'AlertDialog',
      'SimpleDialog',
      'CustomDialog',
      'ResponsiveDialog'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'AlertDialog'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Which package can be used for building adaptive layouts in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'flutter_adaptive',
      'adaptive_layout',
      'flutter_adaptive_layout',
      'flutter_layout_builder'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'flutter_adaptive_layout'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the most common screen size used for mobile devices in Flutter development?',
    'answers': ['360x640', '1080x1920', '1440x2960', '750x1334'],
    'CorrectAnswer': '360x640'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Spacer widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To add padding to a widget',
      'To create a flexible space between widgets',
      'To add margin to a widget',
      'None of the above'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a flexible space between widgets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a MediaQuery in Flutter?',
    'answers': ['A widget', 'A class', 'A package', 'A plugin'],
    'correctAnswer': 'A class'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a Flexible widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make a widget draggable',
      'To change the size of a widget based on available space',
      'To add a margin to a widget',
      'To add padding to a widget'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To change the size of a widget based on available space'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a SafeArea widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To add some padding to a widget',
      'To make a widget scrollable',
      'To ensure a widget is not hidden behind system UI elements',
      'To make a responsive layout'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To ensure a widget is not hidden behind system UI elements'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a LayoutBuilder widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create a responsive layout',
      'To add a margin to a widget',
      'To make a widget draggable',
      'To change the size of a widget based on available space'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a responsive layout'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a responsive design in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A design that adjusts to fit any screen size',
      'A design that looks good on a specific screen size',
      'A design that only works on iOS devices',
      'A design that only works on Android devices'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A design that adjusts to fit any screen size'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a Expanded widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To put padding in a widget',
      'To make a widget draggable',
      'To change the size of a widget based on available space',
      'To make a layout responsive'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To change the size of a widget based on available space'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of a SingleChildScrollView widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make a widget scrollable',
      'To add padding to a widget',
      'To create a responsive layout',
      'To change the size of a widget based on the available space'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To make a widget scrollable'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of a MediaQuery.of(context).size in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To get the size of the device screen',
      'To get the size of a widget',
      'To make a layout responsive',
      'To cause a widget to be scrollable'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To get the size of the device screen'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a IntrinsicWidth widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make a widget draggable',
      'To change the size of a widget based on available space',
      'To ensure a widget has a minimum width',
      'To add padding to a widget'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To ensure a widget has a minimum width'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a SizedBox widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create a fixed size box',
      'To create a draggable widget',
      'To make the size of a widget change based on available space',
      'To ensure a widget has a low width'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a fixed size box'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of a FractionallySizedBox widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make a widget draggable',
      'To make a fixed size box',
      'To ensure a widget has a minimum width',
      'To change the size of a widget based on available space'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To change the size of a widget based on available space'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the TextEditingController in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To manage the text input of a TextField widget',
      'To create custom text editors in Flutter',
      'To access the text of a Text widget',
      'To create and manage animations in Flutter'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To manage the text input of a TextField widget'
  },
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsAPI = [
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Navigator class in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To manage a stack of pages or routes',
      'To manage the state of widgets',
      'To manage network requests',
      'To manage device sensors'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To manage a stack of pages or routes'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is an API in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A set of protocols and tools for building user interfaces',
      'A platform for creating mobile apps',
      'A set of tools for managing database connections',
      'A set of functions and protocols for interacting with external services'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A set of functions and protocols for interacting with external services'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the http package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create animations and graphics',
      'To manage user interface elements',
      'To manage device sensors',
      'To make HTTP requests and handle responses'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To make HTTP requests and handle responses'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the shared_preferences package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To manage user authentication and authorization',
      'To store and retrieve small amounts of data',
      'To make animations and graphics',
      'To manage sensors in devices'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To store and retrieve small amounts of data'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the geolocator package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To manage user authentication and authorization',
      'To create animations and graphics',
      'To make HTTP requests and handle responses',
      'To get the current location of the device'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To get the current location of the device'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the geocoding package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make animations and graphics',
      'To manage device sensors',
      'To convert a geographic coordinate to an address and vice versa',
      'To create HTTP requests and handle responses'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To convert a geographic coordinate to an address and vice versa'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the flutter_map package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create animations and graphics',
      'To effectively manage device sensors',
      'To render maps and handle user interaction with them',
      'To make HTTP requests and handle responses'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To render maps and handle user interaction with them'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the web_socket_channel package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To manage device sensors',
      'To create HTTP requests and handle responses',
      'To make animations and graphics',
      'To handle WebSocket communication'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To handle WebSocket communication'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the url_launcher package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make HTTP requests and handle responses',
      'To handle device sensors',
      'To create animations and graphics',
      'To launch URLs in the platform\'s default browser or app'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To launch URLs in the platform\'s default browser or app'
  },
  {
    'question': 'The FutureBuilder widget in Flutter is to build a widget...',
    'answers': [
      'based on a Future that is resolved asynchronously',
      'that returns a Future when it is tapped',
      'that has a loading spinner until its data is available',
      'that is displayed for a certain duration and then disappears'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'based on a Future that is resolved asynchronously'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Image.asset() method in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To load an image from the application\'s asset bundle',
      'To load an image from the internet',
      'To create a new image asset in Flutter',
      'To manipulate an existing image asset in Flutter'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To load an image from the application\'s asset bundle'
  },
  {
    'question': 'The purpose of the Navigator.push() method in Flutter is?',
    'answers': [
      'Push a new route onto the navigator stack',
      'Pop the current route from the navigator stack',
      'Replace the current route on the navigator stack with a new one',
      'Go back to the previous route in the navigator stack'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Push a new route onto the navigator stack'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the DateTime class in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To represent a point in time',
      'To format dates and times in Flutter',
      'To perform calculations with dates and times in Flutter',
      'To represent time intervals in Flutter'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To represent a point in time'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the http package in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make HTTP requests to a server',
      'To manage local storage in a Flutter application',
      'To create and manage animations in Flutter',
      'To build and manage user interfaces in Flutter'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To make HTTP requests to a server'
  },
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsSTATEManagemnt = [
  {
    'question': 'What is state in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'Data that changes over time',
      'A type of widget',
      'A function that builds widgets',
      'A way to style widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Data that changes over time'
  },
  {
    'question': 'The difference between StatefulWidget and StatelessWidget is?',
    'answers': [
      'StatefulWidget is mutable, while StatelessWidget is not',
      'StatelessWidget is mutable, while StatefulWidget is not',
      'StatelessWidget is a type of StatefulWidget',
      'StatefulWidget is a type of StatelessWidget'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'StatefulWidget is mutable, while StatelessWidget is not'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is setState() in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A function that updates the state of a widget',
      'A function that creates a new widget',
      'A function that destroys a widget',
      'A function that builds a widget'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A function that updates the state of a widget'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is an InheritedWidget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that passes data down the widget tree',
      'A widget that creates a new widget',
      'A widget that updates the state of a widget',
      'A widget that destroys a widget'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A widget that passes data down the widget tree'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is Provider in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A package for state management',
      'A type of widget',
      'A function that builds widgets',
      'A way to style widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A package for state management'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is BLoC in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A pattern for state management',
      'A type of flutter widget',
      'A function that builds and rebuilds widgets',
      'A way to style widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A pattern for state management'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is Redux in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A package for state management',
      'A type of widget',
      'A function that builds widgets',
      'A way to customize widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A package for state management'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a Stream in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A sequence of asynchronous events',
      'A type of flutter widget',
      'A function that listens to widget actions',
      'A way to style widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A sequence of asynchronous events'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a StreamBuilder in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that rebuilds itself when it receives new data from a stream',
      'A widget that builds itself based on a predefined layout',
      'A widget that displays a list of items in a scrollable view',
      'A widget that displays a modal dialog box'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that rebuilds itself when it receives new data from a stream'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is an InheritedWidget?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that shows a list of items in a scrollable view',
      'A widget that displays a modal dialog box in the screen',
      'A widget that animates its children'
          'A widget that passes data down the widget tree to its descendants',
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that passes data down the widget tree to its descendants'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of ValueNotifier in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To hold a single value and notify its listeners when its value changes',
      'To manage the state of an entire application',
      'To display a list of items in a scrollable view',
      'To display a modal dialog box'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To hold a single value and notify its listeners when its value changes'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a ChangeNotifier in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that displays a list of items in a scrollable view',
      'A widget that displays a modal dialog box',
      'A class that extends ValueNotifier and provides methods to change its value',
      'A class notifies its listeners when its value changes'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A class that extends ValueNotifier and provides methods to change its value'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the difference between InheritedWidget and Provider?',
    'answers': [
      'InheritedWidget is low-level API',
      'InheritedWidget and Provider provide the same functionality',
      'Provider is mainly to aid navigation',
      'InheritedWidget is mainly to aid navigation'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'InheritedWidget is low-level API'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the StreamController in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create a stream and add data to it manually',
      'To manage the state of an entire application',
      'To display a list of items in a scrollable view',
      'To display a modal dialog box'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a stream and add data to it manually'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a BLoC in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A design pattern used for state management',
      'A widget that can be used to listen for streams of data',
      'A way to define custom events',
      'A tool for debugging widget errors'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A design pattern used for state management'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is Provider in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A third-party package used for state management',
      'A widget that can be used to create streams of data',
      'A way to define custom events in Flutter',
      'A tool for debugging widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A third-party package used for state management'
  }
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsWidget = [
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Scaffold widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create a basic visual structure for a Flutter app.',
      'To handle the routing system within a Flutter app.',
      'To manage the state of a Flutter app.',
      'To handle network requests in Flutter apps.',
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a basic visual structure for a Flutter app.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the MaterialApp widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create the basic visual structure of a Flutter app.',
      'To handle routing and navigation within a Flutter app.',
      'To manage state for a Flutter app.',
      'To handle network requests in a Flutter app.',
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To handle routing and navigation within a Flutter app.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the ListView widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To display a list of items in a scrollable view.',
      'To manage state for Flutter apps.',
      'To manage network requests in a Flutter app.',
      'To create a basic visual structure in the Flutter app.',
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To display a list of items in a scrollable view.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Text widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To display static text on the screen.',
      'To display dynamic text on the screen.',
      'To manage state for a Flutter app.',
      'To handle network requests in a Flutter app.',
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To display static text on the screen.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the InkWell widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To handle user taps on a widget.',
      'To display a list of items in a scrollable view.',
      'To create a basic visual structure for a Flutter app.',
      'To manage the present state for Flutter apps.',
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To handle user taps on a widget.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the SizedBox widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Adding fixed space between widgets',
      'Creating boxes with custom sizes',
      'Defining widget constraints',
      'Laying out widgets in a grid'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Adding fixed space between widgets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Expanded widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Expanding widgets to fill available space',
      'Creating flexible layouts',
      'Adding padding around widgets',
      'Centering widgets within a container'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Expanding widgets to fill available space'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the ListView widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Displaying a scrollable list of widgets',
      'Creating a grid of widgets',
      'Laying out widgets in a row',
      'Adding padding around individual widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Displaying a scrollable list of widgets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the GestureDetector widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Detecting user gestures on a widget',
      'Displaying an image',
      'Creating a grid of widgets',
      'Adding padding around widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Detecting user gestures on a widget'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Positioned widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Positioning a widget within a Stack',
      'Creating a flexible layout',
      'Displaying a scrollable list of widgets',
      'Adding padding between widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Positioning a widget within a Stack'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Hero widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Animating transitions between screens',
      'Creating a grid of widgets',
      'Laying out widgets in a row',
      'Adding padding around widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Animating transitions between screens'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the TextField widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Accepting user input',
      'Displaying text',
      'Creating a grid of widgets',
      'Laying out widgets in a certain position'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Accepting user input'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the SafeArea widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Ensuring widgets are not obscured by device insets',
      'Creating a grid of widgets in columns',
      'Laying out widgets in a row',
      'Adding padding around widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Ensuring widgets are not obscured by device insets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the FloatingActionButton widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Creating a button for common actions',
      'Displaying a scrollable list of widgets',
      'Laying out widgets in a column',
      'Adding padding between widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Creating a button for common actions'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Card widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Creating a styled container for content',
      'Creating a grid of widgets',
      'Laying out widgets in a row',
      'Adding padding around widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Creating a styled container for content'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the PositionedDirectional widget?',
    'answers': [
      'Positioning a widget within a Stack in a specific direction',
      'Creating a flexible layout',
      'Displaying a scrollable list of widgets',
      'Adding padding around rows and columns'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'Positioning a widget within a Stack in a specific direction'
  },
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsFlutterLayout = [
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a Spacer widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create empty space between widgets',
      'To adjust the size of a widget',
      'To add a border around a widget',
      'To create a responsive layout'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create empty space between widgets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the main axis in a Row or Column layout in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'The direction in which the widgets are laid out',
      'The direction perpendicular to the widgets',
      'The direction of the device screen',
      'The direction of the device camera'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'The direction in which the widgets are laid out'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a SizedBox widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To create a box with a specific size',
      'To add padding around a widget',
      'To create a border around a widget',
      'To create a responsive layout'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a box with a specific size'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the SafeArea widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To ensure that content is not obscured by device-specific features',
      'To create a border round a widget',
      'To add padding within widgets',
      'To create a responsive layout for devices'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To ensure that content is not obscured by device-specific features'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the crossAxisAlignment property in a Row or Column layout in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To control the horizontal alignment of the widgets',
      'To control the vertical alignment of each of the widgets',
      'To control the size of the widgets',
      'To control the color of the widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To control the horizontal alignment of the widgets'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the mainAxisAlignment property in a Row or Column layout in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To control the vertical alignment of the widgets',
      'To control the horizontal alignment within widgets',
      'To control the height of the widgets',
      'To control the size and position of the widgets'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To control the vertical alignment of the widgets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of an Expanded widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To expand a widget to fill the available space',
      'To shrink a widget to fit its content',
      'To create a border around a widget',
      'To create a responsive layout'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To expand a widget to fill the available space'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a Flexible widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To make a widget flexible and allow it to take up only the space it needs',
      'To make a widget fixed and prevent it from resizing',
      'To create a border round a widget',
      'To shrink a widget to fit its inner contents'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To make a widget flexible and allow it to take up only the space it needs'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a Wrap widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To wrap its children to the next line when they exceed the width of the container',
      'Allows widgets to be wrapped and displayed in multiple lines.',
      'To wrap its children to the next column',
      'To wrap its children to the next screen.'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'Allows widgets to be wrapped and displayed in multiple lines.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a SizedBox widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To add a fixed width and height gap between widgets',
      'To make the widgets stretch and fill the available space',
      'To display a list of items in a grid-like fashion',
      'To position a widget relative to its parent'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To add a fixed width and height gap between widgets'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a Spacer widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that takes up remaining space in a Row or Column',
      'A widget that positions its children relative to its parent',
      'A widget that applies padding to its children',
      'A widget that displays a list of items'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A widget that takes up remaining space in a Row or Column'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Expanded widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To expand a child widget to fill the available space in the main axis',
      'To add padding around a widget',
      'To display a list of items in a grid-like fashion',
      'To position a widget relative to its parent'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To expand a child widget to fill the available space in the main axis'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Flexible widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To allow a child widget to have flexible width/height in a Row/Column',
      'To add padding in a widget',
      'To position a widget relative to its parent or child',
      'To force a child widget to have a fixed width/height'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To allow a child widget to have flexible width/height in a Row/Column'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the LayoutBuilder widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To provide information about the constraints passed to its parent widget',
      'To position a widget relative to its parent',
      'To display a list of items in a grid-like fashion',
      'To create a responsive layout'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To provide information about the constraints passed to its parent widget'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the MediaQuery widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To retrieve information about the device size and orientation',
      'To add padding around a widget',
      'To position a widget relative to its child',
      'To retrieve information about the device battery level'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To retrieve information about the device size and orientation',
  }
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsFlutter = [
  {
    'question': 'What is Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'UI toolkit',
      'Database',
      'Backend language',
      'Frontend language'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'UI toolkit',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What programming language is used in Flutter?',
    'answers': ['Java', 'Kotlin', 'Dart', 'Swift'],
    'correctAnswer': 'Dart',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a StatefulWidget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'Handle user input',
      'Display text',
      'Manage state',
      'Make HTTP requests'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Manage state',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a Flutter widget?',
    'answers': [
      'A container for text',
      'A button',
      'A graphical element',
      'A networking library'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A graphical element',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a Flutter package?',
    'answers': [
      'A collection of widgets',
      'A collection of assets',
      'A collection of plugins',
      'A collection of animations'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A collection of widgets',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Flutter Inspector?',
    'answers': [
      'To view and edit code',
      'To view and edit the UI',
      'To manage dependencies',
      'To view and edit app settings'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To view and edit the UI',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Flutter SDK?',
    'answers': [
      'To write code',
      'To compile code',
      'To run code',
      'All of the above'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'All of the above',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the main advantage of using Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'Faster development',
      'Better performance',
      'Easier maintenance',
      'Lower cost'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Faster development',
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the difference between StatelessWidget and StatefulWidget?',
    'answers': [
      'StatelessWidget cannot have child widgets',
      'StatefulWidget cannot be rebuilt',
      'StatelessWidget cannot manage state',
      'StatefulWidget cannot handle user input'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'StatelessWidget cannot manage state',
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the purpose of the pubspec.yaml file in a Flutter project?',
    'answers': [
      'To configure the project',
      'To manage dependencies',
      'To set up the UI',
      'To define routes'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To manage dependencies',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the MaterialApp widget in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To define the app\'s theme',
      'To manage state',
      'To handle user input',
      'To make HTTP requests'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To define the app\'s theme',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the setState() method in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'To rebuild the widget',
      'To set the app\'s state',
      'To manage the app\'s theme',
      'To create and handle user input'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To rebuild the widget',
  },
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsHotReload = [
  {
    'question': 'What is Flutter hot reload?',
    'answers': [
      'It allows you to quickly see changes made without having to restart your app.',
      'A way to speed up your app\'s performance.',
      'A debugging tool used to track errors in your code.',
      'A framework for building web applications.'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'It allows you to quickly see changes made without having to restart your app.'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the difference between Flutter hot reload and hot restart?',
    'answers': [
      'Hot reload applies changes without resetting the app',
      'Hot restart applies changes without resetting the app',
      'Hot reload and hot restart have same functionality',
      'Hot reload is not related to app development'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Hot reload applies changes without resetting the app'
  },
  {
    'question': 'How do you initiate a hot reload in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'Save changes in the editor or IDE',
      'Restart the device',
      'Connect to a different device',
      'Run the app for the first time'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Save changes in the editor or IDE'
  },
  {
    'question': 'How do you initiate a hot restart in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'Stop and restart the app',
      'Save changes in the editor or in the IDE',
      'Connect to another device',
      'Uninstall and reinstall the app'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Stop and restart the app'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the benefit of using hot reload in Flutter development?',
    'answers': [
      'It allows you to see the changes you make to the app immediately',
      'It increases the size of the app',
      'It slows down the development process',
      'It makes the app more complex'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'It allows you to see the changes you make to the app immediately'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the benefit of using hot restart in Flutter development?',
    'answers': [
      'It resets the app state to its initial state, which can be helpful in certain cases',
      'It speeds up the development process',
      'It allows you to see the changes you make to the app instantly',
      'It reduces the size of the app'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'It resets the app state to its initial state, which can be helpful in certain cases'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'How long does it typically take for hot reload to apply changes to the app state?',
    'answers': [
      'A few milliseconds',
      'A few seconds',
      'A few minutes',
      'It depends on the complexity of the app'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A few milliseconds'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'How long does it typically take for hot restart to restart the app?',
    'answers': [
      'Few seconds',
      'Few milliseconds',
      'Minutes',
      'It all depends on the complexity of the app'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Few seconds'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'Can you use hot reload and hot restart in conjunction with each other?',
    'answers': [
      'Yes, you can use both hot reload and hot restart.',
      'No, you must choose between using hot reload or hot restart',
      'Hot reload and hot restart are the same thing',
      'Hot reload and hot restart are not related to app development'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Yes, you can use both hot reload and hot restart.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the disadvantage of using hot reload?',
    'answers': [
      'It can lead to app crashes.',
      'It may not preserve certain types of state.',
      'It can only be used in certain development environments.',
      'It can be slow to inject new code changes.'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'It may not preserve certain types of state.'
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What happens if there are errors in the code during hot reload?',
    'answers': [
      'The app continues to run with the old code.',
      'The app crashes and needs to be restarted.',
      'The new code is not injected in the app.',
      'The app displays an error message and stops running.'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'The new code is not injected in the app.'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the keyboard shortcut for hot reload in Flutter?',
    'answers': ['Ctrl + S', 'Ctrl + R', 'Ctrl + H', ' Ctrl + P'],
    'correctAnswer': 'Ctrl + R'
  }
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsFlutterUI = [
  {
    'question': 'What is Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'User interface toolkit for building natively compiled applications',
      'A programming language',
      'A database management system',
      'A front-end web development framework'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'User interface toolkit for building natively compiled applications',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'To create visually appealing and responsive user interfaces',
      'To manage server-side logic and data storage',
      'To provide advanced machine learning capabilities',
      'To facilitate real-time collaboration'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To create visually appealing and responsive user interfaces',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What are some advantages of using Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'Hot reload feature allows for faster development and testing',
      'Ability to create a single codebase for both iOS and Android apps',
      'Large and supportive developer community',
      'All of the above'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'All of the above',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What are widgets in Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'Building blocks for user interfaces',
      'A type of database',
      'A way to manage server-side logic',
      'A way to communicate with hardware devices'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Building blocks for user interfaces',
  },
  {
    'question':
        'What is the difference between stateful and stateless widgets?',
    'answers': [
      'Stateful widgets can hold mutable state.',
      'Stateful widgets are more performant than stateless widgets',
      'Stateless widgets can hold mutable state.',
      'There is no difference.'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'Stateful widgets can hold mutable state.',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the build method in a widget?',
    'answers': [
      'To build and return the widget tree for that widget',
      'To update the state of the widget',
      'To handle user input events',
      'To make HTTP requests to an API'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To build and return the widget tree for that widget',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a layout in Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'The arrangement of widgets on the screen',
      'A way to manage server-side logic',
      'A way to communicate with hardware devices',
      'A type of database'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'The arrangement of widgets on the screen',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a container widget in Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that provides a rectangular visual element',
      'A widget that plays audio and video content',
      'A widget that manages scrolling content',
      'A widget that provides a text input field'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A widget that provides a rectangular visual element',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the scaffold widget in Flutter UI?',
    'answers': [
      'To provide a basic structure for the app layout',
      'To create and manage animations',
      'To provide access to the device\'s hardware sensors',
      'To interact with the device\'s file system'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To provide a basic structure for the app layout',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of a BoxDecoration in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'to add a background color to a widget',
      'to add a border to a widget',
      'to add a shadow to a widget',
      'to add an image to a widget'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'to add a border to a widget',
  },
  {
    'question': 'How can you add an image to your Flutter app?',
    'answers': [
      'Image.network',
      'Image.asset',
      'Image.file',
      'any of the above'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'any of the above'
  },
  {
    'question': 'How can you add a custom font to your Flutter app?',
    'answers': [
      'download the font file and add it to your project',
      'use a Google font by specifying the font family',
      'use a system font by specifying the font family',
      'all of the above'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'all of the above'
  }
];

List<Map<String, dynamic>> questionsScrollableViews = [
  {
    'question': 'What is a ListView in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that displays a scrollable list of items',
      'A class that allows you to navigate between screens',
      'A package for managing state in Flutter apps',
      'A design pattern for building user interfaces'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'A widget that displays a scrollable list of items',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a SingleChildScrollView in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that displays a single child and allows you to scroll it',
      'A package for managing states in Flutter apps',
      'A design pattern for building user interfaces',
      'A class that allows you to navigate inbetween screens'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that displays a single child and allows you to scroll it',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a CustomScrollView?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that can combine multiple scrollable widgets into a single scroll view',
      'A package for managing state in Flutter apps',
      'A class that allows you to navigate between screens',
      'A design pattern for rebuilding user interfaces'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that can combine multiple scrollable widgets into a single scroll view',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a GridView in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that displays a collection of items in a grid format',
      'A class that allows you to navigate through screens',
      'A package for managing the state of Flutter apps',
      'A design pattern for building user interfaces'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that displays a collection of items in a grid format',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a CustomScrollView sliver in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that can be used to create custom scroll effects',
      'A class that allows you to navigate between screens',
      'A package for managing state in Flutter apps',
      'A design pattern for customizing user interfaces'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that can be used to create custom scroll effects',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a SliverAppBar in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that provides a material design app bar that can be scrolled away',
      'A package for monitoring the state in Flutter apps',
      'A class that allows you to navigate between two screens',
      'A design pattern for building user interfaces'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that provides a material design app bar that can be scrolled away',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a NestedScrollView in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A widget that can be used to create a scroll view with a flexible header and body',
      'A package for managing state.',
      'A design pattern for creating beautiful user interfaces',
      'A class that allows you to navigate between screens'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A widget that can be used to create a scroll view with a flexible header and body',
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is a ScrollController in Flutter?',
    'answers': [
      'A class that can be used to control the position of a scroll view',
      'A package for monitoring the state in Flutter apps',
      'A design pattern for building user interfaces',
      'A widget that displays a scrollable list of items'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A class that can be used to control the position of a scroll view'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the GestureDetector widget?',
    'answers': [
      'To detect user gestures such as taps and swipes',
      'To provide a layout for widgets',
      'To handle user input with forms',
      'To create animations'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To detect user gestures such as taps and swipes'
  },
  {
    'question': 'Difference between a StatelessWidget and a StatefulWidget?',
    'answers': [
      'A StatelessWidget can be updated.',
      'A StatefulWidget is used for more complex UI layouts',
      'A StatelessWidget is used for more complex UI layouts',
      'A StatefulWidget can be updated, but a StatelessWidget cannot'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'A StatefulWidget can be updated, but a StatelessWidget cannot'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the SizedBox widget?',
    'answers': [
      'To create a fixed size box for layout purposes',
      'To create a scrollable area for content',
      'To provide padding around other widgets',
      'To display an icon or image'
    ],
    'correctAnswer': 'To create a fixed size box for layout purposes'
  },
  {
    'question': 'What is the purpose of the Positioned widget?',
    'answers': [
      'To position a widget relative to the top, bottom, left, or right edge of its parent',
      'To provide a layout for widgets',
      'To handle user input with forms',
      'To create animations'
    ],
    'correctAnswer':
        'To position a widget relative to the top, bottom, left, or right edge of its parent'
  },
];
